Finding Aid for the Nan Britton Papers, 1902-1966
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Documentary Files
  - Photo of Elizabeth Ann with her Harding book. June 1921., Nan Britton's note: ... taken in back yard of my sister E's apartment on La Fayette Parkway, Chgo ... (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Nan Britton holding Elizabeth Ann, September 1920., Nan Britton's note: Taken in front of apt. house where lived the nurse who took care of E.A. for over a year. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pressed flower from President Harding's desk in the White House, June 1921., Nan Britton's note: See episode 62, p.156 [The President's Daughter]. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Page from The Marion Daily Star containing a photograph of Nan Britton at age 5, February 1, 1902. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Remaining empty pages of diary kept by Nan Britton, n.d., Nan Britton's note: ... the written pages torn out and destroyed at the request of Mr. Harding to my sister Elizabeth who confided to him that I was keeping the diary. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Facsimile of registration of G.H. Harvey wife, Cleveland, at the Imperial Hotel, New York, n.d., Nan Britton's note: ... facsimile of Mr. Harding's registering of us ... (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Draft of The President's Daughter, with editorial markings, n.d., Nan Britton's note: ... My carbon copy was subsequently destroyed by me. Also, because of very personal allusions in my statement for Mr. Ashley, the original 'legal' manuscript, writeen for the attorney, was destroyed by me. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Draft of Honesty or Politics (original title Stony Limits), n.d., Nan Britton's note: ... many passages were cut out at the suggestion of the critic who viewed it. (Clifton Fadiman) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Lillian Knell to Nan Britton with clippings re Warren G. Harding, June 19, 1926., Lillian Knell was the niece of Mrs. Jack (Mary) Pusey. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - School report of Elizabeth Ann Harding (Willits) which appears in The President's Daughter, opposite p.280, June 4, 1925. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letter (carbon copy) from Nan Britton to the New York Times re permission to use Nan Britton's poem The child's eyes in a forthcoming book and their reply, January 20, January 26, 1920., With facsimile of Nan Britton's first check received for the sale of any writing and a clipping of The Times, August 30, 1926 with the printed poem. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Helen Evans to Nan Britton and Nan Britton's reply (carbon copy), November 3 November 5, 1927., Helen Evans was Nan Britton's nurse at the time Elizabeth Ann was born. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Telegram from Nan Britton to Mrs. Elizabeth Willits re President Harding's death, August 3, 1923., Nan Britton's note: Elizabeth, her husband and Elizabeth Ann we re visiting Scott Willits' mother and father at the time, at their country home near Keithsburg, Illinois. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Postcards of The Claypool Hotel, McFarland Hotel, and Witherill Hotel n.d., Nan Britton's note: See The President's Daughter, pp.37-39 and 57-60 where these are mentioned. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bankbooks. 4 items, 1919-1921., Nan Britton's note: ... monies given to me by Mr. Harding ... (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Campaign poster likeness of President Harding which hung on Nan Britton's bedroom wall, n.d., Reproduced in The President's Daughter, p.12. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Elizabeth Ann to her mother Nan Britton, 1926., Nan Britton's note: ... (written when she was in 2nd grade ina a Chicago public school). Reproduced in The President's Daughter, p.372. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - High school senior oration by Nan Britton, notations by Abigail Harding, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The autobiography of me by Nan Britton, 1921., Written for a class assignment at Columbia University. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Today's Health, with A day with Papa by Nan Britton, pp.30-33, 90-91, February 1966., Based on a brief sketch in The autobiography of me. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - At the keyhole of the Cabinet Room, New York Times, June 5, 1921., With photocopy. Nan Britton's note: See p.155, 1st paragraph, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photograph of Nan Britton holding Elizabeth Ann, 1921., See p.164, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Warren G. Harding. 2 items, n.d., Photographs by Harris Ewing See opposite 164, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding, n.d., See opposite p. 173, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photograph of the White House, n.d., Photo copyright by Ernest L. Crandall. See p. 156, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of the White House. 2 items, n.d., Copyright by Ernest L. Crandall. See opposite p. 189, The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding, n.d., Copyright by Edmonston Studio, Washington, D.C. Note by Nan Britton: Reprints of other photos or pictures appearing opposite pp.129, 134, 160, 180, 204 in The President's Daughter are in my 'Harding scrapbook.' (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript for French translation by Louis Postif of The President's Daughter, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Harry Winfield Saxton to the Editor of the Boston Post, October 29, 1927., Saxton was a member of the Armstrong tour, the group Nan Britton traveled with to Dijon in the summer of 1923. See episode 103, pp.248-249 in The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Letter from Elizabeth Ann to her mother, Nan Britton, September 21, 1927., See opposite p. 340 in The President's Daughter. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence of Addison B. Colvin, 1930-1931., Re the Harding Memorial Association. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Letters re opening of Nan Britton's mail by the Post Office, 1930, 1932, 1933., Letter from William Marsteller, November 1, 1930, Nan Britton, October 30, 1930, Nathan Loeser, October 31, 1930, Jessie Conley, March 17, 1932 and Nan Britton's reply, May 3, 1932. 2 letters from Nan Britton's mother, February 1, 1930 and Fall 1930. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Letter from office of F.E. Scobey to Nan Britton and Nan Britton's reply and related clipping, September 8 12, 1924., Clipping is about the death of Frank E. Scobey, 1931. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Affidavit of Mrs. Marietta Tonnesen, November 16, 1926. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Affidavit of Helen J. Evans and statement by Nan Britton, October 22, 1919; October 27, 1926., Helen J. Evans was nurse to Nan Britton when Elizabeth Ann was born. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Judge Louis B. McNeal and copy of Warren Harding's last will and testament, January 5, 7, 9, 1928., Nan Britton's note: Figures on attached legal-size yellow paper must be those of my attorney, Mr. Kelley. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Adverse and semi-adverse reviews and comments, some humorous, on The President's Daughter. 1927-1928., 13 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. Duplicates. (Box 4, Folder 4-16)
  - Favorable and semi-favorable reviews and comments on The President's Daughter, 1927-1928., 2 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Establishment of paternity avoided in Toledo trial (Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk), 1931., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Notices re personal appearance and talk at 55th St. Theatre (with showing of motion picture Children of No Importance]. 1928., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Notices of bestsellers which included The President's Daughter - Author daughter in pose (photograph only), 1927-1929., 8 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 4, Folder 21-28)
  - Material re Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk, 1928-1931., Folder 1 of 7. Clippings and preservation copies. Includes letters from Nan Britton to the St. Louis Post Dispatch, August 6, 1928 and to the Buffalo Times, August 7, 1928. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Material re Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk, 1928-1931., Folders 2 through 7 of 7. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 5, Folder 2-7)
  - Publicity acquired by Judge Grant E. Mouser, 1927-1928., 9 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 5, Folder 8-16)
  - Reviews of A Dead President Makes Answer, 1928., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence re Wightman suit, including copy of statement by Richard Wightman, 1927-1928., 4 folders. (Box 5, Folder 18-21)
  - Material relating to Warren G. Harding's inauguration and death, 1921-1930., 4 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 6, 1920., Preservation photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 6, 1920., Original issue. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 22, 1920., Preservation photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 22, 1920., Original issue. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New York Herald Tribune, February 15, 1931., Preservation photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - New York Herald Tribune, February 15, 1931., Original issue. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Standard Star, New Rochelle, November 21, 1931., Preservation photocoopy. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Standard Star, New Rochelle, November 21, 1931., Original issue. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Review of Reviews, September 1923., Containing Harding, Man and President by Judson C. Welliver. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Beautiful Ohio, vol.2 no.3, 1960., re Marion, Ohio. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Bystander, no.1396 vol.107, September 17, 1930., re The President's Daughter. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Nation-Wide Review, December 1927., re Nan Britton. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The New Yorker, October 22, 1927., See pp.14 and 102. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Confidential Love Secrets, January-February 1956., re President Harding's Tragic Love Affair by Kit Carroll. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Junior League Magazine, October 1927., re The President's Daughter. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Haldeman-Julius Monthly, June 1928., Interview with Nan Britton and Elizabeth Ann Harding. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The New Republic, September 28, 1927., Review of The President's Daughter. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper articles relating to the dedication of the Harding Memorial, 1931., 3 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Material re Charles Forbes after his release from Leavenworth penitentiary, 1927., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Material re John S. Sumner raid to seize printing plates for The President's Daughter, 1927., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Material re U.S. Post Office and Department of Justice Investigations into Elizabeth Ann League, 1927., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Material re proposed libel bill and Nan Britton's position, 1927-1928., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Material re Representative John N. Tillman's characterization of The President's Daughter before Congress, 1928., Clippings and preservation copies. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 5, 1922., 4 folders. Centennial issue. Box 7 is an oversize flat box, 15 19. (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - Various newspapers regarding the death of President Harding, 1923., 2 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Material re screen rights to The President's Daughter, 1927-1928., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clippings re 3 books about Harding, 1927-1929., The Inside Story of the Harding Tragedy, by Harry M. Daugherty, Revelry, by Samuel H. Adams, The Whispering Gallery, by an English Ex-Diplomat. With preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Humorous (?) clippings re The President's Daughter. 1928., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Material re The Strange Death of President Harding, by May Dixon Thacker, 1930-1931., 3 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
  - Material re Teapot Dome, 1928, 1964., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Publicity resulting from the discovery of the Phillips letters. 1931, 1946, 1964., Clippings with preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Reviews and comments on Honesty or Politics by Nan Britton, 1932., 3 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Suits brought against the Elizabeth Ann Guild, 1927., Clippings and preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous clippings v.d., 2 folders. With preservation photocopies. (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - Nan Britton's Harding scrapbook 1920-1923., With photographs, clippings, campaign literature, campaign buttons. Fragile. Box 18 is an oversize flat box, 15.5 19.5. (Box 18, Folder 1)